

+971 56 8960162

amithapsugathan@gmail.com

Dubai - UAE

EDUCATION

MCA [Master of Computer Application]

2008 - 2011

Bachelor of Computer Science

2005 - 2008

CERTIFICATIONS

International Software Testing Qualifications Board [ISTQB] Foundation Level Exam, 2024

Software Automation Testing -Selenium WebDriver + Java

SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER [ISTQB Certified]

Profile

With over an experience of 8 years in IT & Non-IT industries and a proven track record in Quality Assurance, my understanding of software testing has derived outstanding results. Biggest career achievements include significantly improving software quality and user satisfaction.

⊕ Work Experience

SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER

EXPRESSARE TECHNOLOGIES
TRIVANDRUM, KERALA, INDIA
20 NOV 2023 - 13 NOV 2024

SENIOR EXECUTIVE

WIPRO LTD | INFOPARK KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA 19 MARCH 2021 - 16 AUG 2023

CONTENT WRITER

WORDSLINE | KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA 1 OCT 2018 - 12 MARCH 2021

CONTENT WRITER

CREATOR
KAKKANAD, KOCHI, KERALA
1 SEP 2017 - 28 SEP 2018

SOFTWARE TESTER & TECHNICAL SUPPORT

XTEND TECHNOLOGIES | KOCHI, KERALA 6 SEP 2013 - 10 SEP 2014

PROCESS EXECUTIVE

SPECTRUM SOFTECH SOLUTIONS (P) LTD | KOCHI, KERALA 24 FEB 2012 - 13 OCT 2012

SKILL SET

- QA AUTOMATION
- MANUAL TESTING
- SELENIUM WEBDRIVER
- JENKINS
- MAVEN
- TestNG
- POM
- BUG REPORTING Jira
- GitHub
- Bigbucket
- TEST CASE PREPARATION
- TEST CASE EXECUTION
- TECHNICAL DOCUMENT PREPARATION
- UI/UX TESTING
- JAVA

WORK HISTORY

SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER

EXPRESSARE TECHNOLOGIES TRIVANDRUM, KERALA, INDIA 20 NOV 2023 - Present

- Collaborated with software developers, product managers, and other stakeholders to identify and prioritize testing requirements.
- Preparing and executing automated/manual test cases.
- Responsible for reviewing and analyzing system specifications.
- Spearheaded a cross-functional team to adopt Agile methodologies.
- Implemented Automated test cases using Selenium WebDriver.
- Utilized Java to develop test scripts, shortening the testing phase.
- Participated in daily/weekly product team meetings to provide insightful feedback on user experience and potential improvements.
- Reporting bugs to software developers using Jira.
- Introduced continuous integration processes using Jenkins.
- Working with cross-functional teams to ensure the quality of software applications.
- Responsible for documenting various functionalities of applications.
- Contributed to the maintenance of high-quality standards that met customer needs.
- Revolutionized the company's testing processes by enhancing test accuracy and stakeholder communication.

SENIOR EXECUTIVE

WIPRO LTD | INFOPARK KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA 19 MARCH 2021 - 16 AUG 2023

- Developed and Executed test cases for manual testing.
- Reporting test progress to the development team, resulting in effective communication and resolution.
- Performed Functional, Regression and UI testing.
- Skilled in understanding Software requirement Specification and identifying the required Test scenarios.
- Professional Software testing Experience that includes Effective Test case Designing and Test case preparing.
- Analyzed test results and reported issues to development teams for resolution.

CONTENT WRITER

WORDSLINE | KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA 1 OCT 2018 - 12 MARCH 2021

- Prepared technical documents, including website content, blog posts, articles, for IT & Non-IT companies.
- Handling social media platforms, including Facebook and Twitter (now X).
- Training junior content writers about the company's requirements and help them meet quality, productivity and deadlines.

CONTENT WRITER

CREATOR KAKKANAD, KOCHI, KERALA 1 SEP 2017 – 28 SEP 2018

- Responsible for preparing website content, blog posts, articles and content for various social media platforms.
- An additional duty of handing social media platforms of educational institutions in Tamil Nadu.
- Preparing taglines, brand names, titles, motto, and banner content

SOFTWARE TESTER & TECHNICAL SUPPORT

XTEND TECHNOLOGIES | KOCHI, KERALA 6 SEP 2013 - 10 SEP 2014

- Performed Exploratory testing on emerging software features for an IVR system.
- Performed Smoke, Load and UI/UX Testing for the IVR system.
- Providing technical support for telecommunication clients.
- Streamlined the bug tracking process.
- Collaborated closely with software developers to build better solutions.
- Actively participated in daily stand-up meetings.
- Preparing technical documents for the IVR system.

PROCESS EXECUTIVE

SPECTRUM SOFTECH SOLUTIONS (P) LTD KOCHI, KERALA 24 FEB 2012 - 13 OCT 2012

- Assisted a team handling an online bidding system.
- Performed Exploratory testing of the bidding system.
- Prepared technical documents on the new features for the client.
- Participated in the daily meetings to ensure the quality of the system.

PERSONAL DETAILS

• DOB : 01 August 1987

• Nationality : Indian

Passport number : Y5816699 | Expiry: 03/07/2033

• Visa Status : Visit Visa

• Availability : Immediate

• Language Proficiency : English, Hindi, Tamil, Malayalam

• Marital Status : Married

MY LIFE PHILOSOPHY

Build strong relationships and achieve successful outcomes!